Senior Software Engineer Ronak Bhatt

ronakbhatt.in

% +91 9601195650

ronakabhattrz@gmail.com

43/b,3 Adarsh apt Jagabhai Park, Maninagar Ahmedabad-380008, Gujarat, India

in Ronak Bhatt LinkedIn

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Dedicated Senior software engineer with 5+ years of experience as a full stack developer. I to seek a position to utilize my skills, and abilities and apply my knowledge in software development in a reputed organization and want to secure my future.

EDUCATION

Diploma in computer engineering

Swaminarayan College of engineering 2009–2014, Gandhinagar, India

Bachelor of engineering in computer engineering

Sal institute of technology

2014-2017, Ahmedabad, India

KEY SKILLS

Fluent in English, Time management
Ruby , Rails, Git, Gitlab, Jira Heroku, Aws, Docker
PostgreSQL, Mysql HTML/CSS/JS, react js, Bootstrap
Javascript, Jquery, Ajax, Typescript, Next Js
ElasticSearch, CI/CD, Rspec, Agile, deployment,
rubymine, API Integration, Redis, Memcached,
Heroku, DigitalOcean, MVC

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Bulletproof (Cyber Security) - Remote
Jan 2022- Present, Stevenage, England, UK

- Embedded test-driven development practices into existing processes to elevate the quality of code.
- worked on several APIs, Third-party Integration, Mostly working with Ruby on rails (full stack).

Senior Software Engineer (Promote to Team Lead)

Crest Data System - On Site

May 2021-Jan 2022, Ahmedabad, India

 As a full-stack developer working with React.js, Next.js, and Ruby on Rails, and also managing projects and handling client communication

Senior Software Engineer

Mainstreet USA (Now rename to Hoist)- remote Aug 2020-April 2021, Los Angeles, CA, US

 I mostly work with Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, RSpec, and follow the Agile methodology with a focus on Test-Driven Development (TDD).

Software Engineer

Upwork - Freelance June 2017-July 2020

 I mostly work with Ruby on Rails, API design, frontend technologies like HTML5, CSS3, and JQuery, as well as modern frameworks like React.js, and GraphQL. Proficient in database management, code versioning, deployment, and integrating APIs for payment systems and other services.

HOBBIES & LIKES

Socialising with friends and family

Jamming with friends, singling

Traveling with Bike (Rlding)

Ruby On Rails Intern

Complitech Solutions Private Limited - Fulltime Jun 2016 - May 2017

 Complitech is built with a well-structured team of professionals. Knowledge sharing environment here boosts the enthusiasm within us and increases team spirit. I learned lots of things From Mr Tejas Shah.

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES

- Self-taught, proactive, responsible, results-oriented.
- Technical skills: Ruby on Rails, API Design, HTML5/CSS3/JQuery, Bootstrap, Web-Based Application, GraphQL API, Databases (Postgres, SQLite, MySql), Code versioning (GitHub, Bitbucket), Deployment (Heroku, AWS, S3), Open source, Background Jobs (Sidekiq, delayed job, Redis), API Integrations (Stripe, Paypal), Development Tools (Trello, Slack, Jira, Bitbucket).
- Specialization: Cloud-based Accounting, ERP projects, E-Commerce, Financial projects, API integrations, Blogs/Websites, Developing websites from scratch.
- Please check the website on which I have worked: https://www.ronakbhatt.in/project.